if you are brand new to the ipad or if
you just want to expand your knowledge
when it comes to the different settings
and features that are available then
this is the video for you here fresh
from costco is a brand new 12.9 inch
ipad pro and we are going to crack this
thing out and we are going to go through
the entire setup process and i'm going
to review all of the different settings
that i recommend i'm also going to teach
you all of the most important
multi-touch gestures and so much more
heads up folks this video will be a lot
longer than my normal videos so if you
would like to skip ahead at any point in
time please know i will put time codes
with their respective chapters down
below in the video description new to
ipad coming up next on tech talk america
all right folks here it is the moment of
truth here's the seal let's open this
puppy ready
here we go
and let her let her drop out
so here we have it brand new 12.9 inch
ipad pro there you go
let's start with talking about some of
the different buttons and some of their
functions here on the top of the ipad is
appropriately named the top button if
you press and hold it that turns on your
device if you click it once after it's
already on that puts it to sleep
if we rotate the ipad here we have the
volume buttons up and down if you press
the top button and the volume button at
the same time that's how you take a
screenshot
over the course of this setup process
there are going to be some parts that
i'm going to fast forward just to save
time as i said a moment ago when you
press and hold the top button that's how
you turn on the ipad when you do you'll
see the apple logo and eventually it
will bring us to a welcome screen i'll
now swipe up from the bottom and select
my language as well as my country
quick start is an option if you already
own an iphone or ipad and you just want
to simply copy all of the information
from either of those other devices to
your new ipad if so then you can use
this feature but for this purpose we're
going to set things up manually i'll now
need to select my wireless network so
i'll just type in that information real
quick
in just a moment you'll see the data and
privacy screen and i am not going to go
into that because none of you care let's
hit continue
and at this point we're going to be
prompted to set up face id i'm going to
skip this for this demonstration it's
absolutely something that all of you
should do at this point you're going to
hold up your ipad and it's going to ask
you to look left look right look up look
down and scanning your face so that you
can use your face for several different
functions you can use it for unlocking
your ipad you can ultimately use it for
purchases that you make using apple pay
and one of the best functions is you can
use it for filling your passwords
even if you use face id you still have
to create a passcode now as you can see
here it's asking me to create one that
is six digits long i always tell people
look this is not really the password
that you have to be so concerned about
making complex that's other stuff so i'm
gonna change this over to a four digit
passcode and i'm gonna do the thing that
you should never ever do and i'm gonna
make it one one one one and as you can
see here my ipad did not like that it
says it's too easily guess well guess
what this thing's getting wiped as soon
as we're done with this demonstration so
let's make it one one one one we're now
given several different ways that we can
transfer data from other devices
including a mac pc
an android device another ipad for this
demonstration we're going to not
transfer any of that data
at this point i'm going to need to
either enter my apple id or if you don't
already have one you're going to need to
create one in case you're not familiar
with the term an apple id is an identity
that you create in order to purchase
apple products and services for example
icloud apple music or apps that you may
purchase in the app store
terms and conditions i'm going to spend
as much time talking about this as you
will reading it
i fast forwarded this next part quite a
bit your ipad goes through a bit of a
setup process it takes a few minutes tap
continue at this point it's going to ask
you about location services in general i
do recommend allowing location services
if you want to deny it to any apps you
can always do that on an individual
basis but overall it's a good idea
this next screen is going to ask you if
you want to set up apple pay we're not
going to do it right now but i do want
to say that in general i think it's a
really good idea to have apple pay and
to register all of your different credit
cards with it and the biggest reason why
i recommend it is because that way
anytime there's a charge on your credit
card you get a push notification about
it now in general i don't like
notifications but that's one
notification that i do want to know
about so that's the reason why i do
generally recommend that you set up
apple pay even if you don't use it on a
regular basis it's now going to ask if
you'd like to use icloud keychain this
is the part of icloud that can allow you
to store and sync your passwords it's
not a great solution for everyone and
whether or not it's right for you comes
down to what devices you own and what
web browsers you use if you ever need
help with password management it's
quickly become one of my specialties at
this point you can choose whether or not
to enable siri which is the voice
assistant in general i do absolutely
recommend it if you go through this
process it's going to ask you to choose
which voice you want it to use and
you're going to have to read a few
different phrases into the microphone
you're going to see this screen to
improve siri and dictation i absolutely
do recommend that you use it and for
those of you out there who have trouble
with siri understanding you you probably
said no and that's why it's not getting
better
and on to screen time here's my general
recommendation don't use it yes you're
on your devices too much yes you neglect
your kids yes you neglect your pets the
floors could use a good scrubbing and
it's probably because you play too much
candy crush ipad analytics up to you in
general no
when it comes to appearance i don't
recommend either of these there's
actually a third option that for some
strange reason is not presented on this
screen so pick whatever you want i'll
show you how to change it in just a
moment
and welcome to ipad let's get started
and here we have the home screen but
before we break down the home screen the
first thing that i want you to do if you
just got a brand new ipad is to go into
settings then tap on general then tap on
software update and make sure that it is
up to date
as you can see here mine isn't so i'm
going to run that update and we'll be
right back
and welcome back wasn't that last
commercial of hoot at this point what i
would like us to do is to go back into
settings there are a lot of settings
that come one way and i recommend that
you change to another way so let's start
by tapping on your name here at the very
top i now want you to tap on where it
says password and security and here at
the bottom you will see an option to add
something called a legacy contact this
feature is essentially how to create a
digital will and was covered in a recent
video that i created this is something
that i recommend every single iphone or
ipad user take the time to do more than
anything this is about protecting your
photos if you would like to learn more
about that feature feel free to check
out my video again called how to create
a digital will let's now tap to go back
a page and then let's tap into icloud
icloud is essentially a storage service
run by apple yes i do recommend it it's
a great easy way to backup and sync
several aspects of your data but that
being said it might not be something
that you want to use for everything for
example for me on my iphone i use icloud
to store and sync my entire photo
library but on my ipad i really don't
care about having all of my photos i
really just want my favorites if that
sounds like something that you might be
interested in the way that you do that
is you plug your ipad into your computer
and then you can choose from there to
only sync specific albums one of the
options that i would like to clarify
because a lot of people find it
confusing if you were to tap on where it
says icloud mail in that process you are
actually creating a brand new email
address that would end in at icloud.com
now some of you may be looking to create
a new email address and if you are
bombarded by junk mail this works very
well with the hide my email address so
let's say you find something online that
you find pretty and want to buy if you
use this feature what it will do is when
you create the account that buys that
item what it will allow you to do is
create a completely random email address
that way if you get on their mailing
list you can shut it down
let's now go back to the main menu
obviously i'm skipping over some parts
here because otherwise we'd be here all
day let's go here into notifications my
general advice is to turn most of these
off except for the important ones so for
me i like to turn on notifications of
course for messages as well as facetime
calls but for things like tips no let's
now skip down to focus mode this is a
relatively new feature to ipad os where
you can allow your ipad to go into
different levels of do not disturb mode
and you can allow certain exceptions so
for example if there are certain work
colleagues that you want to be able to
get through you can add them maybe you
have family members you can add them
if we go back to the previous window
here you will see an option to share
focus mode across your other devices so
for example if i turn focus mode on my
iphone it will share that status to my
ipad some people like that others don't
let's now go back into general settings
and from here i'm going to tap on about
this is where you can find all the most
important information about your ipad
including what version of ipad os it's
running the serial number the amount of
available space total capacity and more
let's go back a screen and talk about a
few other features starting with airdrop
airdrop is a really amazing technology
that you can use if you ever have either
photos or video files and you want to
send them from your device to someone
else's device who is physically present
it's the absolute fastest way to move
data you can choose to receive airdrop
files either from everyone only your
contacts or you can turn this feature
off
there's technically two different ways
that you can uninstall apps on your ipad
one of them is to go here into ipad
storage and then tap on the app that you
want to remove let's go with garageband
and then tap delete app
now you can repeat that process with any
other apps that you don't actually use
here at the top you'll see i have a
recommendation to offload unused apps
i'm definitely going to turn that one on
that will also help prevent me from
overstuffing my ipad
let's now go into the settings for
control center and before we get into
the settings i want to show you how to
access it to access control center pull
down from the top right corner of your
ipad here you'll see a ton of helpful
settings i'll explain what each of those
does in greater detail in just a moment
but for now what i want you to do is go
through this list and look for any other
tools that you might find useful for
example i love having the apple tv
remote available the keyboard brightness
and that's specifically for any of you
who happen to buy the magic keyboard
accessory also i love having easy access
to low power mode and screen recording
so now when i pull down from the top
right corner you'll see that all of
those tools that i just added are here
at the bottom again we'll come back to
this later on let's now go into display
and brightness you remember during the
setup process that i mentioned that
there's actually a third option in
regards to light mode versus dark mode
well what i recommend you do is turn on
automatic that way once the sun goes
down it's going to flip my ipad
automatically from light mode to dark
mode and then in the morning it'll
switch it back
the next setting that i recommend you
check out is night shift mode if you
decide to schedule it what this will do
is it will make the white balance of
your ipad shift to warmer tones towards
the end of the day let's once again go
back to the previous menu and now let's
go into auto lock as you can see here
your ipad by default will lock after two
minutes if you'd like to be a little bit
longer you can make that adjustment here
let's now go back once again and now
let's go into text size for those of you
who have issues with your vision this is
where you can change all of the text
across the board so that everything
appears larger let's now go back once
again you'll also see an option to make
all of the text bold so for those of you
who need a little bit more contrast
that's what it looks like the next
option you'll see in this list is
display zoom if we go back to what my
home screen looks like this is what it
looks like in standard mode i'm going to
do a quick fast forward this is what it
looks like if i choose zoomed so as you
can see here we have less room for apps
but everything in general is larger
let's now tap into wallpaper options and
then tap on choose a new wallpaper if
you want to go with one of the options
provided by apple we have dynamic and
still images to choose between dynamic
wallpapers move and while they're really
cool the problem that i have with them
is these do generally use up a lot more
battery life so i tend to recommend that
you either choose from one of these
still images or you can use one of your
own photos one of the nice things about
many of these options provided by apple
is you see all these options that have
what appears to be a split screen what
that means is that it's going to shift
again from light mode to dark mode once
the sun goes down obviously this is a
demo machine but this is the wallpaper
that i actually use on mine i just
really love the coloring of it it gives
it a nice personality plus it's
functional if we go back to the previous
window you'll notice all of these here
are albums that are coming over from my
photos notice we just set up this ipad
and it's already synced over all of my
photos so if you're trying to find a
photo from your own photo library the
easiest way to find it is just put in an
album and then you can pull it up here
in wallpaper if you skip the part where
we set up siri at the very beginning if
we go into the menu settings here you'll
see the option to turn on the h-e-y siri
yes i'm spelling it so i don't set off
all your devices feature on your ipad
again you'll go through the exact same
training you'll have to say a few
phrases out loud and the one little
thing i want to emphasize is you should
not read it like you're reading it you
want to actually say it like you would
normally just say it out loud i have
three privacy related settings that i
would like you to check out the first is
here under tracking allow apps to track
hmm let me think about that for a minute
turn it off
now let's go into apple advertising and
here you'll find an option for
personalized ads
my advice turn
it off
and finally let's jump down to settings
for safari and here you'll find an
option to prevent cross-site tracking if
we go here into mail settings this is
where you can add any other email
accounts to your ipad all you have to do
is tap on where it says add account and
then you can choose from any of those
options or if it's something else just
tap on where it says other and you'll
have to enter in your username and
password one of the most common problems
new ipad owners encounter is they
discover that they have different
information stored in different places
so for example if i were to add a gmail
account to my ipad gmail like icloud
also has the ability to store and sync
things like contacts calendars and notes
so if you discover that you have
duplicate data or missing data whether
it's contacts calendars or notes the
most likely cause is a syncing issue
taking place in this part of settings if
you ever need help resolving those types
of issues i'm happy to help you if you
book a one-on-one session with me which
of course you can do through my website
link in the video description
one of the settings you'll definitely
want to check out here in calendar
settings is your default calendar so
whenever you create a new appointment
what calendar do you want it to talk to
that does it for all the most important
settings i wanted to cover so let's now
go back to the home screen you probably
saw me do this earlier but anytime you
want to exit an app all you need to do
is swipe up from the bottom with one
finger
let's now take a moment to talk about
what you see on the screen here at the
top we have a few examples of widgets
including the weather a preview of my
notes calendar and a large clock if you
want to add edit or remove a widget just
press and hold on it to add a widget
press and hold on any app and then tap
on where it says edit home screen
now tap the plus symbol at the top left
on the right hand side of the screen we
have some popular widgets but if i tap
on any of the apps on the left hand side
you will discover that many of these
widgets come in different sizes where
they display different amounts of
information so let's say you're
constantly working with people who live
in different parts of the world you
might want to consider going to the
clock widget and if we swipe to the side
you'll see that there's an option to add
a widget that displays multiple time
zones if you follow the stock market and
want to keep an eye on some of your top
performing stocks you might want to
consider checking out one of the
different stock widgets another option
is you can create something called a
smart stack these are swipeable widgets
that can contain information from
multiple apps i don't personally use
smart stacks but i'm definitely a fan of
the traditional type when it comes to
deleting apps you have a few different
options if you press and hold on an app
you will see an option to remove it if i
tap on that i get two additional options
i can completely delete it or if i'm
just trying to clean house i can remove
it from my home screen but it will still
live in the app library the fastest way
to get to the library is you'll see it
here at the bottom right of my dock the
other way to get to the app library is
just swipe to the last page of apps and
then tap into where it says app library
if you want to group apps together into
a folder just press and hold on it and
then tap edit home screen once your apps
go into jiggle mode you can drag one
into the other in order to create a
folder your ipad will suggest a name for
this folder but if you would like to
change it to something else it's as easy
as tapping into the title let's now go
over some of the most important
multi-touch gestures that you can use on
your ipad let's start with an easy one
if i'm in an app and i want to go back
to the last app that i used all i need
to do is use four fingers and swipe from
left to right
one of the most important multi-touch
gestures that we need to cover is how to
get into the app switcher to do this
it's very similar to how you get back to
the home screen the only difference is
you need to add a pause i'm going to
drag my finger from the bottom center of
the screen up and once i hit the middle
of my ipad i'm going to let it hang out
for a second and then let go
now you can see all the apps that i have
running in the background if i want to
completely quit an app from running all
i need to do is swipe up on it another
option is you can run two apps side by
side to do that from the app switcher
all you need to do is drag and drop one
app into the other if you want to give a
little bit more room to one app over the
other just drag this vertical bar to the
side
if you ever want to exit split screen
view just drag the vertical bar all the
way to the side so that it exits the
screen
notification center is where you can see
every notification from all of your apps
that have it enabled
to do that it's very similar to the way
that you access control center but
instead of swiping down from the top
right this time we're going to do it
from the top center
speaking of control center let's go back
to that which again we get to by swiping
down from the top right here at the top
left of this list we have quick
shortcuts to access airplane mode
airdrop
wi-fi and bluetooth settings many of
these settings actually have multiple
options which you can access by long
pressing on it so for example if i want
to adjust my airdrop settings i can long
press into it to access those options
this button will lock the rotation of
your ipad which is really helpful if
you're watching something like a movie
and maybe your ipad is laying down flat
on a table if you have apple tv the box
not the service you can mirror your ipad
to your tv by tapping on this option i
also have sliders for volume and screen
brightness if i long press into
brightness controls you'll see that i
have options to manually turn on dark
mode night shift and true tone you
remember how the wallpaper i chose
earlier has both a light and dark mode
well when i flip this switch you can see
how it looks to turn your ipad off just
press and hold the top button as well as
either of the volume buttons when you
see this screen just swipe to turn it
off i'd now like to show you how to use
copy and paste to copy press and hold on
the area of text that you want to select
now i can drag either of these dots to
select my text then just tap on copy
now let's say i want to paste this into
an email all we need to do is double tap
and then select paste
if you ever make a mistake that you need
to undo check this out all you need to
do is shake your ipad then you'll get a
pop-up asking if you'd like to undo the
last move i don't want to talk too much
about accessories in this video but
there are two that i would like to
recommend the first is the magic
keyboard this product is made by apple
and i'll warn you in advance it is not
cheap but if you're looking for an
amazing keyboard for the ipad it's a
superior option plus one of the things i
love about the magic keyboard is that it
has a trackpad that means i don't have
to touch the screen nearly as much and
that means that my screen has fewer
fingerprints on it another accessory
that i'm a big fan of are these
multi-functional cables for example this
one here gives me usb type a and c on
one side and usb c and lightning on the
other side these cables are really
inexpensive if you'd like to pick one up
i'll put a link in the video description
thank you so much for watching everyone
keep in mind if you would ever like to
work with me privately that is one of
the things i do and i've come to refer
to this as tech therapy you can sign up
for a one hour session by visiting my
website at techtalkamerica.com
thank you for watching if you haven't
already done so please take a quick
moment and hit that thumbs up like
button leave me a little comment down
below and if you haven't already done so
please subscribe to my youtube channel
thank you so much for watching everyone
this is david a cox with tech talk
america class dismissed
[Music]